Erik Kimsey

Frontend Developer / Creative Technologist

Tenacious *UI Developer / Creative Technologist*. Specialize in developing beautiful, dynamic, and intuitive user-interfaces. Over 5 years of professional experience, collaborating with multi-disciplinary teams and clients. Utilizing a breadth of *languages, technologies, UI / UX design*, and *strong communication skills*. Agile and DRY. Not shy of *creating bespoke elements of other multimedia* (graphic design, 3D modeling, music / sound design, and more).

~ Core Skill Set ~

Javascript · React · Typescript · React Native · C#. Recently: Swift / SwiftUI · C++

Professional Experience Professional Experience

Frontend Engineer | Peripheral Brain (PBrain)

Next.js • Javascript • React • CSS • Material UI • Docker

11/2022-06/2023

- Decreased mobile-data usage by as much as 400%, by implementing state-management techniques.
- Improved user-experience by developing a closable-tabs feature to PBrain open "Editor" components.
- Reduced codebase inter-dependency, by modularizing features into individual React components.
- Increased accessibility, to potential customers and mobile users, by adding to and refining the the UI's responsiveness.
- Increased PBrain's performance and codebase's readability by removing redundant logic, unused logs, and unnecessary comments.

Software Engineer / UI + UX Designer | Moxie

11/2021 - 06/2023

React Native • Javascript • Three.js • C# • Unity3D • Swift / SwiftUI • Blender

- Engineered 3 small prototypes of Moxie, testing Moxie's UI requirements (highly-stylized, dynamic, interactive features) against the capabilities of: React Native, C#/Unity, and SwiftUI + Swift Frameworks.
- Architected Moxie's preliminary frontend structure and backend schemas, based off of its user-stories.
- Created over 50 visual, audio and UI assets (incl. 3D models, sprite graphics, and shaders).
- Drafted Moxie's business and marketing plan.

UI Engineer I University of Virginia + Sartography

Typescript • React Native • Python • SQLite • Node.js

09/2020 - 03/2021

- Engineered over 90% of the UI for the mobile application "SkillSTAR"; therein, designed the mobile application's architecture.
- Reduced project costs by \$30,000, by performing the roles of UI designer and project manager.
- Implemented the "Chaining Educational Model" as a complex, recursive algorithm using Typescript.
- · Orchestrated weekly meetings with the SkillSTAR clients, to discuss development progress.
- · Created custom graphic assets, using Illustrator and Photoshop, used throughout the application.
- · Collaborated with backend engineers to design database schema and Rest endpoints.

Frontend / Full-Stack Engineer various contracts	2018 - 2020
Javascript Engineer ChartlQ ("Cosaic")	2016 - 2017
Studio Recording Technician Rosetta Stone	2012 - 2016
Supervisor Westover Park Skatepark	2006 - 2012

Education Education

Bachelor of Science, Philosophy I James Madison University I 2010 Graphic Design Certificate I Blue Ridge Community College I 2012 Lambda School I Software Engineering I 2019 Post-BS Computer Science I Oregon State University I 2017